<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Drafts on Home</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/</link><description>Recent content in Drafts on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cooking</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/cooking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/cooking/</guid><description>Rice Ingredients
100g of rice salt and pepper 200ml of water Steps:
Wash the rice 3 to 4 times Boil the water Add the rice in boiling water for 10 minutes with the lid on Stop the fire and leave it with the lid on for 10 minutes</description></item><item><title>Games</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/games/</guid><description>Hades Death&amp;rsquo;s door Rainbow Six: Siege Destiny 2 Call of duty: Warzone Bastion Transistor Pyre Cyberpunk 2077 Crying Suns Bioshock 1 Biosock 2 Bioshock Infinite Splinter Cell: Blacklist Far Cry 3 Far Cry 4 Far Cry: New Dawn Far Cry 5 Far cry: Blood dragon Thief Styx: Master of Shadows Dishonored Control Ori and the Blind Forest Ori and the Will of the Wisps Morkredd Stealth Inc. 2: A Game of Clones Portal 2 Bridge Constructor: Portal Death Squared Frostpunk Marvel vs Capcom Moonlighter Neon Abyss Mortal Kombat Katana Zero A Plague Tale: Innocence Overcooked 2 Unruly Heroes World war z Vambrace Cold Soul Wasteland 3 Skyrim Shank Lineage 2 Wow Guild wars 2 The elder scrolls online Tera Aion BadNorth Don&amp;rsquo;t starve Together Hearthstone League of Legends Legends of Runeterra Valorant Counter-Strike 1.</description></item><item><title>Jokes</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/jokes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/jokes/</guid><description>Dad jokes I asked my date to meet me at the gym today. She didn’t show up.
That’s when I knew we weren’t gonna work out.
Today a man knocked on my door and asked for a small donation to the local swimming pool.
I gave him a glass of water.</description></item></channel></rss>