<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>blog on Home</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://danielmititelu.github.io/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A few words about bit manipulation</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/bit-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/bit-manipulation/</guid><description>Bit manipulation is not a technique that comes often when writing code especially when dealing with higher level languages, regardless it is useful to understand how computers work behind the scene.
Bit The smallest data use to represent a piece of information in computers are bits and they represent an electrical current that is stored in a memory chip. This bit can either be on or off and the notation 1 and 0 from binary system is used to denote it&amp;rsquo;s state.</description></item><item><title>A few words about Graph theory</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/graphs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/graphs/</guid><description>A graph is a collection of vertices(V) or nodes(N) connected with edges (E)
Types of graphs Trees A graph with V-1 edges is a tree
Binary Trees A tree where each vertices has zero or two children</description></item><item><title>English</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/english/</guid><description>than/then - than is comparison; then is time related.
despondent - in low spirits from loss of hope or courage
bustle - move in energetic and busy manner
flatly - showing little interest or emotion
mien - a person appearance or manner, especially an indication of their character or mood
perfunctory - carried out without real interest, feeling or effort
inadvertently - without intention, accidentally
bespectacled - wearing glasses
bellitle - to make an action or a person seem unimportant</description></item><item><title>Jokes</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/jokes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/drafts/jokes/</guid><description>Dad jokes I asked my date to meet me at the gym today. She didn’t show up.
That’s when I knew we weren’t gonna work out.
Today a man knocked on my door and asked for a small donation to the local swimming pool.
I gave him a glass of water.</description></item><item><title>System design</title><link>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/system-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmititelu.github.io/blogs/system-design/</guid><description>Databases Database management systems (DBMS) which are usually referred to as just databases are a piece of software that are used stores data in an organized way and offer an API to interact with it.
Depending on the way data is organized and accessed there can be different databases paradigm and we will explore a few of them here.
Relational databases Examples: PostgreSQL, MySql, Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server
The most common way to store data is using tables with rows, columns and having relations between them.</description></item></channel></rss>